Brian Salehi

Updated: July 21, 2022

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

con

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/
briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

Tehran, Iran

Brian Salehi

Software Engineer

Professional Summary C and C++ programmer having 3+ years of experience. Expertise in developing Linux systems and services, having indepth knowledge of operating systems, software design, procedural and object-oriented programming, clean coding, debugging, and writing precise and comprehensive documentation. Interested in the open source movement, spending some of my spare time making open source tools or contributing to open source projects. Planning to join the Kernel development cycle.

Experiences

Software Engineer

Arad Company

Iran (aradtechs.com)

05/2021 - 05/2022

Contributed to five projects of the company, including network programming, graphics programming, automation services, and continuous integration and continuous delivery echo systems. Completed three projects individually and contributed to two other major projects in two separate teams. Authored dozens of pages of internal reference manuals and documented all of the projects in the company both in web and in source versions.

Bioinformatics Laboratory (cooperation)

Poland (undisclosed)

Software Engineer, Consultant

08/2020 - 05/2022

Consulted on the design and development of computational services and contributed to a few micro-projects in bioinformatics applications. By the end, many projects were successfully developed under my supervision and gradually landed on the laboratory's website. Further disclosure about this operation is not possible.

Sarmad Business Services (cooperation)

Iran (sarmadbs.com)

System Administrator, Database Specialist

04/2021 - 06/2021

Consulted on technical solutions, guided for administering of Linux servers and maintaining the database services, and finally authored many concise and comprehensive documentation for the education of their staff. Under my supervision, all primary services were set up and running by the end of this cooperation.

Training

International (milextone.ir)

Software Engineer, Technical Trainer

03/2019 - present

Trained and supervised 11 college students to Ph.D. graduates in Iran, Germany, Poland, and the United States for teaching fields of studies, including Linux administration, Bash scripting, C, C++, and python programming, and a few development tools. Of all, a few successfully applied for the scholarship for higher educational degrees, and others had job promotions.

Manzoomeh Negaran Holdings Software Engineer, Database Specialist Iran (seller.ir)

06/2016 - 06/2017

onal.	a database of an ind the end of this coop		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		
	:		

Brian Salehi

Email

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/
briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

Tehran, Iran

Skills

Technical

C, C++, Python, Linux System Programming, Bash Scripting, Linux Administration, Qt, QML, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, x86_64 Assembly

Tools

Git, GCC, GDB, Nasm, Sanitizers, Valgrind Suite, Make, CMake Suite, Docker, Doxygen, Sphinx, UML, PlantUML, Vim, Latex

Education

MSc. of Computer Science	iau-tnb.ac.ir
Islamic Azad University	9/2021 - present

BSc. of Computer Science iauet.ac.ir
Islamic Azad University 9/2016 - 06/2021

Certificates

Fanavaran Anisa Ins.	anisa.co.ir
Linux Device Driver	2022
Embedded Linux	2022
Linux Application Development	2021
LPIC-3 Linux Security	2017
LPIC-2 Linux Networks	2016
LPIC-1 Linux Systems	2015

Languages

Persian (Native) English (Fluent) German (Basic)

Interests

Technical

Kernel hacking, embedded Linux, graphics programming, user interfaces, image processing, machine learning, software and hardware design, algorithms, mathematics, quantum mechanics, philosophy, psychiatry

Personal

Playing electric guitar, reading books, swimming, biking, running, hiking

References

Dr. Farhang Jaryani

fjayani@yahoo.com

Faculty of Computer Science, Arak University, Iran